Scientific name -- Equus grevyi
Size -- 55" at shoulder, 880 lbs.
Diet -- grasses, shrubs and small trees

Of the 3 zebra species, the Grevy's zebra is the largest and lives the farthest north in Africa. Anatomically, they resemble horses except for their striking black and white pelt, which helps to camouflage the outline of the animal when viewed at a distance by potential predators. They bray similar to donkeys.

While other zebras form permanent herds, the Grevy's live in temporary social groups. Males can be solitary and territorial, defending the largest territories of any modern herbivore. Zebras generally flee from predators, but do have a strong kick that has been known to kill lions or hyenas, the zebra's main predators.